http://www.ussc.gov/privacy-security-and-comment-policy

Privacy, Security, and Comment Policy | United States Sentencing Commission
The Federal Sentencing Guidelines
The Commission promulgates guidelines that judges consult when sentencing federal offenders. When the guidelines are amended, a subsequent Guidelines Manual is published.
In this section, you will find the Commission’s comprehensive archive of yearly amendments and Guidelines Manuals dating back to 1987.
Research
2019 Sourcebook
Archive
DATA REPORTS
By Geography
By Guideline
By Quarter
Prison Impact Reports
Research & Data Mission
The Commission collects, analyzes, and disseminates a broad array of information on federal crime and sentencing practices.
In this section, you will find a comprehensive collection of research and data reports published on sentencing issues and other areas of federal crime.
Public Access to Commission Data and Documents
Policymaking
Meetings & Hearings
Federal Register Notices
Amendments
Public Comment
The Amendment Cycle
The Commission establishes sentencing policies and practices for the federal courts. Each year, the Commission reviews and refines these policies in light of congressional action, decisions from courts of appeals, sentencing-related research, and input from the criminal justice community.
In this section, you can follow the Commission’s work through the amendment cycle as priorities are set, research is performed, testimony is heard, and amendments are adopted.
Rules of Practice and Procedure
Education
Education Mission
The Commission serves as an information resource for Congress, the executive branch, the courts, criminal justice practitioners, the academic community, and the public.
In this section, you will find resources to assist you in understanding and applying the federal sentencing guidelines.
Glossary of Sentencing Terms
Training Products
Decision Trees
eLearning
Newsletters
Podcasts
Teacher's Edition
Worksheets
About the Commission
The U.S. Sentencing Commission is an independent agency in the judicial branch that was created as part of the Sentencing Reform Act of 1984. Commissioners are nominated by the President and confirmed by the Senate. The Attorney General, or the Attorney General’s designee, and the Chair of the U.S. Parole Commission serve as ex officio, nonvoting members of the Commission.
In this section, learn about the Commission’s mission, structure, and ongoing work.
By Topic
Featured
2014 Drug Amendment
Alternatives to Incarceration
Career Offenders
Crimes of Violence
Demographics
Drug Trafficking
Information Routinely Collected and Stored
Our privacy policy outlines the types of information we learn when you visit us online through our website or third-party social media and how such information will be used.
Website
When you visit our website, the Commission does not request, collect, or record personally identifiable information (PII). If you visit our website to view or download information, we collect and store the following information:
The name of the domain from which you accessed the Internet;
The IP address from which you accessed the Commission's website;
The date and time you access our site;
The type of browser and operating system used to access the Commission's site;
The pages you visit;
If you linked to the Commission's website from another website, the address of the originating site.
This information is used solely for the purpose of evaluating and maintaining our site. From this information, we learn what users like and need; what kind of technology they are using; how often they visit; and other valuable information that helps us to offer the best site possible.
Social Media and Other Third-Party Sites
In addition to the website, the Commission maintains official social media accounts on third-party websites to broadcast Commission work to a wider audience. When you visit official Commission social media pages, the Commission does not request, collect, or record personally identifiable information (PII). Information collected by the Commission will be used solely for the purpose of evaluating and maintaining those accounts. Please be aware that privacy policies of third-party websites may not be the same as the privacy policy governing the Commission's website.
Information You Provide
If you choose to provide us with personal information, perhaps to be placed on our mailing list or to request additional information, it will be used only for the purpose(s) you state. We collect such information only to respond to your requests. We do not share that information with others, and we do not collect information for commercial marketing.
Security Notice
For site security purposes and to ensure that this service remains available to all users, this Government computer system employs software programs to monitor network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause damage.
Anyone using this system expressly consents to such monitoring and is advised that if such monitoring reveals evidence of possible abuse or criminal activity, such evidence may be provided to appropriate law enforcement officials.
Unauthorized attempts to upload or change information on this server are strictly prohibited and may be punishable by law, including the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986 and the National Information Infrastructure Protection Act of 1996.
Comment Policy
Comments Submitted Through Social Media Are Not Official Public Comments.
Comments submitted to the Commission through social media platforms, such as Twitter, are not official for purposes of the Commission’s formal rulemaking process. Official public comments must be submitted directly to the Commission by electronic mail or regular mail during a formal comment period. The email address for public comment is Public_Comment@ussc.gov. The Commission may follow, respond directly to users or repost content. "Follows", "mentions" or "retweets" do not imply bias or endorsement.
Comments Will Be Monitored.
The Commission acknowledges that social media tools are intended to foster a healthy dialogue among users, and it encourages the use of social media for that purpose. The Commission also recognizes that social media users may present various, sometimes divergent, views on issues that impact federal sentencing. Commission staff will monitor all comments posted to Commission accounts through social media outlets. The Commission reserves the right to delete comments. Among the types of comments that will be deleted are comments that:
are overtly political, partisan, or made in support of a political party or a candidate in a political campaign;
contain requests to contact any federal, state, or local government official, including a member of Congress;
include advertisements, endorsements, or promotions of specific commercial services or products;
contain language that is vulgar, abusive, or offensive;
include sensitive or personally identifiable information;
contain threats or defamatory statements; or
advocate illegal activity.
USSC HelpLine
The HelpLine assists practitioners in applying the guidelines.
Disclaimer
Contact: (202) 502-4545
Hours: 8:30 a.m. to 5:00 p.m. (ET) Monday – Friday
U.S. Sentencing Commission
Office of Public Affairs
One Columbus Circle, NE
Suite 2-500, South Lobby
Washington, DC, 20002-8002
Main: (202) 502-4500
E-mail: PubAffairs@ussc.gov
Sign Up for Regular Updates
Privacy and Security
Site Map
Related Links
GuidelinesGuidelines AppDrug Conversion CalculatorDrug Quantity CalculatorSentencing TablePrimers2018 Guidelines Manual AnnotatedArchiveAmendmentsOrganizational GuidelinesResearch2019 SourcebookArchiveDATA REPORTSBy GeographyBy GuidelineBy QuarterPrison Impact ReportsRetroactivity ReportsDatafilesResearch NotesInteractive Data AnalyzerTutorial VideosResearch ReportsReports At A GlanceReports To CongressQuick FactsList of All PublicationsPolicymakingMeetings & HearingsFederal Register NoticesAmendmentsPublic CommentEducationGlossary of Sentencing Terms Training ProductsDecision TreeseLearningNewslettersPodcastsTeacher's EditionWorksheetsSee All Product TypesNational SeminarPrevious SeminarsCase Law ResourcesCase Law ConciergeCase Law QuarterlyPrimersTraining TopicsCategorical ApproachCriminal HistoryMultiple Counts/GroupingRelevant ConductSee All TopicsRequest TrainingMeet the TrainersCLE InformationAboutWho We areCommissionersFormer CommissionersOrganizationAdvisory GroupsEmploymentNewsPress ReleasesTestimony, Submissions, & SpeechesNewsletters2019 Annual ReportArchiveBy Topic
